Guide to the Lyman and Sadie Hale Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Lyman and Sadie Hale Papers
1926-1971
RG 147
Yale University Divinity School Library
1.5
(7 boxes)
Writings, collected material, and glass slides document the Hales' life and work in China. Lyman and Sadie Hale were American Methodist missionaries to China from 1915 to 1941 and 1945 to 1949. They were stationed in Wuhu (1916-1925), Nanking(1925-1927, 1945-1949), Shanghai (1927-1929), and Chinkiang (1929-1941).
Hale, Lyman
Hale, Sadie
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualifed researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lyman and Sadie Hale.
Biographical / Historical
Lyman Hale supervised mission schools and churches in Wuhu from 1916 to 1925, and in Nanking from 1925 until evacuated to Shanghai in March 1927. The Hale family resided in Shanghai from 1927 to 1929, with Lyman serving as mission treasurer and secretary. From 1929 Sep to 1941 (except furlough in 1933-1934) the family resided in Chinkiang, with Lyman serving as mission supervisor and treasurer and editor of The China Christian Advocate; served in Nanking after WW II (1945-1949). The Hales twice had their home completely destroyed due to political disturbances (1927 and 1937).
Scope and Contents
This collection consists primarily of collected material, including valuable typescript and mimeographed accounts of events in China. It contains documentation of 1927 Nanking incident and Japanese occupation 1937-1939, National Christian Council of China Broadcast Bulletins, circular letters from colleagues and friends, correspondence with Methodist mission board, and Chinese language material as well as more than 100 glass slides.
Arrangement
I. Collected Material, 1925-1971, n.d.
II. Correspondence, 1927-1975, n.d.
III. Writings, 1932-1941
IV. Glass slides, n.d.
Methodist Church -- Missions -- China; Missions -- China; Hale, Lyman; Hale, Sadie
- Collected material, 1925-1971, n.d.; Series I
  - Accounts of events in Nanking and Chinkiang, by Lyman Hale and others, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Newspaper clippings re. events in Nanking, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Documents re. Christian education and government regulations, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bulletins from Shanghai Community Church, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Article by Bp. James Bashford, Bible study notes, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, reports, memos re. Methodist missions in China incl. biographical sketches of Bishops W.Y. Chen and Z.T. Kuang, 1933-1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NCCC bulletin re. events in Nanking, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Report of Chinkiang branch of the Nanking International Relief Assn., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Broadcast Bulletins of the National Christian Council of China, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memos from Methodist Board of Missions in NY, 1941-1956 (Box 1, Folder 10a)
  - Conference on American Far Eastern Policy, Syracuse Univ., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Re. Christian literature in China; re. Protestant missions in Nanking, 1943, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Directory of Westerners in Nanking, pub. by Nanking Association, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Misc., incl. "Address of Chiang Kai-shek", re. Nestorian monument, re. Pearl Buck, 1928-1971, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Issues of China Christian Advocate, 1929-1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scripture selections and tracts - in Chinese (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Additional Chinese language material, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chinese hymnal "Hymns of Universal Praise", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1927-1975, n.d.; Series II
  - Primarily from missionaries in China, 1927-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Primarily from former China missionaries, 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
- Writings by Lyman Hale, 1932-1941; Series III
  - "Chinkiang Provices for New Cultural Needs" The Shanghai Times, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Interference or Privilege" China Christian Conference Bulletin, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "The Parable of Plain Marking" (typescript), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Various articles from China Christian Advocate, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Glass slides, n.d.; Series IV
  - Script for glass slides - slide include images of Chinese scenery, ways of life, children, medical work, famine, etc.: (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Produced by Methodist Church of China - Slides #50-1336 (Box 3a)
  - Produced by Methodist Church of China - Slides #1352-1730 (Box 3b)
  - Produced by Methodist Church of China - Slides #2139-2943 (Box 3c)
  - Produced by Methodist Church of China - Slides #3013-3587 (Box 3d)
  - Produced by Board of Foreign Missions, Methodist Episcopal Church, 3 slides (Box 3d)
  - Unnumbered, miscellaneous slides, 7 slides (Box 3d)
  - Easter set, Slides #1-27; Christmas set, 1 slide (Box 3e)